So we get an always spinning fetching process here
Bylece her zaman burada ileme dnyor.
as you can see if you inspect the console, we don't have any errors but we also never get our ingredients
Konsolu incelerseniz, hatalarmz olmadndan da anlalaca gibi, mantkl maddlarmz da asla elde etmemekteyiz, nk
which makes sense because setIngredients which is dispatched once we got the ingredients is never handled
maddeleri bulduumuz zamanlarda gnderilen ayar blgeleri asla yapmcmz tarafndan ele
in our reducer,
alnmamaktadr.
so time to change this,
Bunu deitirmek iin zaman.
the same is true for FETCH_INGREDIENTS_FAILED
Ayn fecche malzemeler baarsz olduu iin de geerlidir.
So in the burger builder file in the reducers folder, I know when to handle these two new cases.
Burger Boulder drcler klasrne dt iin bu iki yeni vakay ne zaman ele alacam biliyorum.
So first of all, I'll add a case for actionTypes.SET_INGREDIENTS, this is executed whenever we got ingredients
her eyden nce ya da eylem trleri iin bir vaka ekleyin.
from the server. There
Bu yzden
I want to return a new state and I'll copy the old state first
Yeni bir eyalet dnmek istiyorum ve nce eski devleti kopyalayacam.
for that reason and then I need to set my ingredients. Here,
Bu sebeple ieriklerimi buraya koymam lazm.
ingredients should be set to action.ingredients and I know that I receive these ingredients because
indekiler harekete geirici maddeler haline getirilmelidir ve ben bu maddeleri aldmn farkndaym, nk burger
in the burger builder action file where we have setIngredients, I do pass this ingredients property.
kasesinde veya hareketi drdmde ierdii maddeleri getiimde bu maddeler mlkiyetini geirdim.
So now I initialize where I set my ingredients and theoretically, we could execute this action or dispatch
imdi reaktiflerimi ayarladm yeri balatyorum ve teorik olarak bu eylemi uygulayabilir veya
this action whatever we want,
ne istersen gnderirim.
so we could also execute this, set this with any set of ingredients with any javascript object representing
herhangi bir noktada maddelerimizi temsil eden herhangi bir javascript nesnesiyle birlikte herhangi bir bileen setiyle yrtebiliriz.
our ingredients at any point of time we want, for example to reset the current people
Bu nedenle, bu ayarlaycy, rnein mevcut insanlara sfrlamay istediiniz zaman
burger. Here however,
Berger kahraman.
I just want to use it to initialize our ingredients.
Ben sadece malzemelerimizi balatmak iin kullanmak istiyorum.
Now with that, I call setIngredients,
imdi bununla birlikte set maddeleri diyorum.
I then also want to handle the other case that the fetching of ingredients failed, there
O halde, malzemelerin alnmasnn burada baarsz olduu davaya bakmak isterdim.
I will also return new state where I copy the old state and then I of course also need to set my error
Eski durumu kopyaladm yeni durumu da geri getireceim ve tabii ki burada da hata ayarlamam gerekiyor ve
here and I want to set it to true, so error
bu yzden hatay true olarak ayarlamak istiyorum.
true.
Doru.
Now one important thing, when we call set ingredients here, I want to set my error to false to reset it
imdi set maddelerini burada ardmzda nemli olan ey, daha nce bir hata yaadmzda hatay sfrlamak
in case we had an error earlier
iin hatay yanl yapmaktr.
and now don't have it anymore, so I'll set my error to
Ve imdi artk sahip deilim, bu yzden hatam kabul et.
false here.
Yanl burada.
So with that, we added our reducer logic,
Dolaysyla bununla birlikte yapmc mantmz ekledik.
now we needed to connect our container,
imdi konteynrmz balamamz lazm.
so I'll head over to the burger builder file and there, at the bottom of this container,
Bu yzden burger Bolar dosyasna gidip onlar da bu kabn altndalar.
we no longer only need the ingredients, we also need to get information about a potential error.
Potansiyel bir hata hakknda bilgi edinmemiz gereken maddelerle artk ilgilenmiyoruz artk.
So here I want to get my error from state
Dolaysyla burada hatam devletten almak istiyorum.
and now there, the error property.
Ve imdi onlar hava ya da mlk.
Keep in mind, thus far we have no different slices of state,
imdiye kadar hibir farkl devlet dilimimiz olmadna dikkat edin.
we only have one reducer,
Sadece bir redktrmz var.
we're not combining any.
Hibirini birletirmiyoruz.
So with that I have my error,
Bu yzden benim hatam var.
now one other thing we have is we never dispatch our initIngredients action,
imdi sahip olduumuz baka bir ey, biz asla bizim malzemelerle harekete gemememiz.
this one which actually reaches out to the web,
Aslnda Web'e ulaan bu.
we never dispatch this
Bunu asla gndermedik.
so this will never get initialized.
Bu yzden bu asla balatlamayacak.
So I also want to be able to dispatch that from the burger builder
Bu yzden de Burgert Boulder'dan bunu gndermek istiyorum.
So I'll add a new property here to mapDispatchToProps,
Bu nedenle, Peche'yi sahneyle buluturmak iin yeni bir mlk ekleyin.
I'll name it
inde isim koyacam.
onInitIngredients and I'll dispatch my burger builder actions here and I need to add the burger builder actions
Malzemeler ve burger ektirici eylemlerini burada gndereceim ve burger Bolar eylemlerini dizin cipslerine eklemeliyim
to the index.js file where I bundled them. Here,
onlar burada paketlediklerim yere dyor.
I need to add
Ona eklemek lazm.
initIngredients.
Malzemeler.
So now, I can reach that from my burger builder container file, initIngredients and execute it.
imdi bunu burger kasemden veya konteyner dosyasndan ieriklerine ulaabilir ve uygulayabilirim.
Now the last step is to call onInitIngredients in our componentDidMount method here,
imdi son adm, Bileenimizdeki bu Da Yntemi'nin herhangi bir bileenini armaktr.
so there I will now execute this.props.onInitIngredients, like this and this should execute this, dispatch
Bylece u anda bu ilemi bu gibi maddeler zerinde uygulayacam ve yemek bu eylemi gndermeli
this action and hopefully successfully fetch our ingredients.
ve umarm baarl bir ekilde malzemelerimi alsn.
Last but not least, we did add this error property to map it to our error state,
Son olarak, bunu, hata durumumuza elemek iin mlkmz olarak ekledik.
now of course I also need to use it and I can simply search for all occurrences of state.error
imdi elbette bunu kullanmam gerekiyor ve basite devlet DOT hatasnn tm durumlarn arayabilir
in my file here, these are the places where I need to use,
veya dosyamda burada bunlar kullanmam gereken yer var.
well except for mapStateToProps,
Eyalet damla haricinde.
so this place here is the place where I now need to call this.props.error because now we're receiving
Buras buras u anda bu pervane hatasn aramam gereken yer nk imdi bunu
this as props. With that,
babamla sahne alyor.
let's save all files and if we go back to our application, let's have a look if we got any errors if
Btn hatalar kurtaralm ve eer uygulamanza geri dnersek, tiap yeniden
we reload the app,
yklersek oklar alalm bakalm.
that looks good to me,
Bu bana iyi geldi.
we got a burger here.
Burada bir burger var.
Let's now have a look at the redux dev tools, we see setIngredients was executed and did set up our
ve imdi maddeleri tekrar eklemeye balayabiliriz ve bu sipari srecini buradan da girebiliriz.
ingredients and now we can start adding ingredients again and we can also enter the order process here,
imdi, hazrlanm bileenlerin uygulandn grdmz redux dev aralarna bir gz atalm ve malzemelerimizi hazrladk
this is all working fine.
Bunlarn hepsini iyi yapn.
Last I want to check if error handling works,
Son olarak hata ileme ie yarayp yaramadn kontrol etmek istiyorum.
so let me head over to my burger builder action creator and let's mess up this URL here,
Bu yzden burger Boulder eylem yaratcs bama gidelim ve burada olduunuza karar vereyim.
let's save it
Haydi kurtaralm.
and this also still works as it should.
Ve bu da yine de gerektii gibi alr.
So this is great,
Yani bu harika.
we can see error handling with our higher order components still works due to us using one and the same
grebilmek iin, yksek sipari bileenleri hala ayn x 'rneinde bir tane kullandmz iin alyor.
axios instance
Hata ileme yntemini
and now we can move on to the other places where we need to use asynchronous code.
Ve imdi, asenkron kodu kullanmamz gereken dier yerleri Vonta'y kullanabiliriz.
The next place of course is when we want to order a burger.
Elbette, bir sonraki hamburger sipari etmek istiyoruz.